here we go
[Music]
oh
that wasn't as quite a bigger splash as
i was hoping
so we begin
all over again where do we even start a
whole new season lies ahead of us we
have absolutely nothing
but the boat we arrived in i can't tell
you how weird this is
to be starting all over again last time
it was my first ever season so
things are a bit different but you know
what we've actually started exactly the
same way i have no idea where i'm going
by the way i literally i'm i'm a little
bit lost to be honest i don't oh mumbo's
here everyone's here the party is
starting i just don't know what to do
i'm i've got too much to do i went from
season six and feeling like
everything had been done to the whole
world in front of me i guess now we've
got to do some basic resource collection
and try and find somewhere to settle our
first base
and i've probably chosen the worst place
to start because i definitely i'm not
going to be doing anything here out in
the mesa
i haven't found anything that isn't mesa
or savannah
oh jungle melons
this is my lucky day what i'm really
hoping to find and mumbo's already got
diamonds
mumbo already has diamonds
parrot you don't like seeds
no no no no no
mr parrot we are going to be best
friends
and we are going to be best friends
forever
how many seeds does it
dude
how hungry are you
this little guy eats more than a family
of four
are you kidding me
he's like yeah i'm full i'm out
what does what does he want
more seeds i could have created a
hundred but no no no no no no we're not
done here we're not done here i'm gonna
force feed you seeds until you love me
come on boy yes
best friends okay are you gonna are you
gonna are you gonna do the thing are you
gonna do do the thing wait where are you
going oh we're meant to be friends now
you you get yes
yes i'm going to call you
professor beak that is your name
professor beak come on professor beak
wait
professor peak no
come on
this is gonna be a nightmare isn't it
that yeah you can't you can't go
anywhere here we go
come on professor beak let's go find
somewhere to live
hello
this is the this is the kind of present
that i want
and i'm taking this too you know what
you can just you could just follow me uh
professor because like you're kind of
bad at this whole staying on my shoulder
thing
so the bit of terrain that we're looking
for is kind of a hill like this but we
want to look for a substantial one
now i really kind of want to go in the
jungle here because it's it's just a
really saturated it's lush and green and
i don't know it's a lot more pleasant
than say the mountains or extreme hills
because they look so
dull and cold the other issue though
with the jungle
is my goodness
is it hard to get
around oh no
yeah you can't get me
i eat melon in your face mr skeleton do
you know what i don't like
walking and neither does mr beak
professor beak
dr b you know what i haven't seen your
qualifications yet we could be looking
for quite some time do you know what
this this will do
this will do quite nicely
i can work with this this will be easy
enough to clear out
let's get started mr beak there you sit
there and have some seeds
because we're about to start clearing
out some of this stuff
[Music]
i was clearing out my base and i
actually went through all the way to the
back here and i discovered something
really really amazing so i covered it
back up so i could reveal there's like a
secret little place here right through
the mountain
i am totally going to do something cool
with this i don't know what yet but this
is like
a little secret garden you wouldn't know
this was here unless you went
specifically on this mountain
so how cool is that not entirely sure
but i need to continue mining stuff out
but now i've got to do something that's
a little more on the boring side as you
can see i've been collecting stuff i
have also made myself a little mine
because
what we got to do now is the thing you
have to do at the start of every
minecraft world
go down and find yourself some
diamonds or redstone which is going to
be something i learned how to use in
this season
last season i don't know what my goal
was it was it was have fun this season
it's have fun and redstone two things
two for the price of one i hear zombies
i hear them i'm getting close oh
it's
this is amazing this is so close to my
base how close am i
really really close well this is a great
start just need to light this up because
this is going to be an early source of
xp for me it's a wow it's a real zombie
party down there okay what we got in
here bread gum powder string the usual
this is brilliant we're gonna save this
hold on i need to lay claim to this
greens spawner
do not touch now in order to use this
i'm gonna have to transport the zombies
up to where my base is because i don't
want to have to come down here for xp
i've learned that the hard way having
all your farms separated is a pain in
the neck so
what we're gonna do we need to oh man i
just realized we got like a a whole
bunch of stuff to do so we need to go to
the nether because we need soul sand
because we need a bubble elevator to
take all this zombie stuff and pop it
over there for us to farm
wait they won't spawn unless i'm close
right how does this work
i need to do a quick a quick bit of
research to find out how close you have
to be to a spawner for them to start
spawning i don't know if i can get away
with transporting these anywhere at all
oh this is so painful i miss
my elytra so much
i've done a little bit of reading and it
turns out you've got to be right next to
the spawner for it to produce something
so it looks like my xp farm is going to
have to be down there but in order to
actually make good use of that i've had
an idea okay so uh look over here this
is one of the most beautiful locations
and i didn't even really realize
there's the most gorgeous lake over here
but there's a
giant dirt box
we got we gotta find out what this sign
says i didn't i didn't make this so this
means that someone has settled close by
to where i am you're a wizard scar okay
it's scar
good times with scar is my neighbor and
this is a great thing i absolutely love
neighbors because
i can go and see what they're up to
although i really don't know what scar
is up to
do you know what where this is scars
placed his base
i'm pretty sure
that the mob spawner down there
is
probably about here
so
you know what when scar gets back on
we're going we're gonna well we're gonna
prank him
we better make sure he knows what it's
like to be next to me
at the beginning of the season so
yeah i'm gonna wait for scar to get on
but we're gonna have to prepare because
i need a lot of resources to make this
work oh my goodness i'm so excited all
right then let's go into the cave and
we're gonna go and do some strip mining
so i haven't found a single diamond
let's go down and find ourselves
something useful
[Music]
i've had some serious bad luck with
mining
eight diamonds well if you count okay
add some tools but eight diamonds is not
great but as you can i mean this shows
just how unlucky i've been right look at
how much redstone and iron blocks and
everything else i got an eight diamonds
that's
that's really really rotten luck but as
you can see i've been making some
progress now i just need to get myself
set up and then i can start working on
the interior of this build
but it turns out good times with scar
who has a beard for some reason he's
working on something over here he's
working on his base
yeah there look he's over there see him
see him you see him with his beard and
his big dirt ball
i think that's a dirt house
oh yeah i forgot i put this on my head i
found a parrot head and i put it i put
it on
hello so
i think that the spawner is somewhere
around here if my
directions are correct and i think we
can make we can make good use of this
and the fact that he has a giant dirt
ball gives it oh this is going to be so
good so now that he's on we're going to
make this happen
we need to go into the nether very very
briefly
hopefully we get good luck
all i need to find is some soul sand
somewhere
soul sand somewhere soul sand somewhere
soul stand right there
might as well might as well get a couple
of blocks of things while we're here
we'll take some quartz for some red
stoney bits i don't want to mine too
much stuff right now because i haven't
got any of my enchantments yet that's
that's what i'm trying to get right now
is why i'm trying desperately not to die
i'm trying to save my 34 levels
and we're gonna get our stuff enchanted
particularly the diamond pick and like
the sword and stuff so that we can get
going and make good use of everything
that we find
okay and now we pop back
as you can see i have i have actually
started some farms
this is just to get me started it's not
for me this is for the cows that i've
got i have been busy collecting a couple
of cows getting them going and then
there's uh i need leather because you
know how it goes you need books for
bookshelves you need bookshelves to
enchant you need levels blah blah blah
blah blah blah so that's that's going on
in the background meanwhile we will go
down here to our zombie spawner
and get them sporting for us so the plan
is that we're going to take
this spawner
and we're going to turn it into a proper
farm but we're not going to use it for
xp just yet we're going to send it all
the way above
to where scar is and then we're gonna
get our camera account and we're gonna
watch scar try and figure out what's
going on meanwhile just zombies are
pouring out everywhere
i need to clear out all of this space
around it
and make sure that we light it up as we
go along we're going to funnel them over
here
for the time being so now we just need
to see where this comes out for scar's
base
scar is still online despite this taking
like an hour
we're gonna get to the surface
we're gonna see where he is and then
we're gonna reassess i haven't seen his
username and that's not a good sign
because i should be approaching the
surface by now that's always a good
no no no no oh no i thought i was gonna
there for a second okay up we go
ah we're really oh did he see me he
might have seen me
i think he saw me
okay so that's a little bit further than
i anticipated but
if we guessed mate
so we need to go
maybe 50 blocks
north
i have a feeling i need ice and i
definitely can't get any ice
for a while
oh dear
i didn't maybe i didn't think of all
this through i might need to make a
beeline at some point for some ice we'll
see if they transport any any sense
no
[Music]
okay bad bad
yep bad
okay we're directly underneath
i don't know how direct i can be with
this
maybe we want to hide it in the jungle a
little bit
just to be safe
ah we'll go here we'll go here so now we
need to make the same one by one tunnel
all the way to the top
you know i really shouldn't i know
you're not supposed to dig straight down
but you also really shouldn't dig
straight up either because some gravel
could come down
anything
he has absolutely no idea
no this is not the place to die this is
not a good place to die there's a
creeper there's a creeper on the corner
nope
oh no
oh thank goodness
oh thank goodness thank you goodness
that
was awful
that was really bad
and i don't even know where
i don't even know where i'm in such a
panic is this it here
okay that's that's the hot or scar's
back up there he's just there
he's right there he's literally
he's literally right there we just need
to know exactly where this comes out
he can probably hear me mining
now that i think about it i don't have
stone i didn't think it's through
let's pop our head out
where is he
he doesn't know
this is perfect
he's right there
i think we want to hide
this in the bush just over there
what we're gonna do
ah
i don't know where he is he's on top of
that
i'm totally gonna i'm totally gonna do
this
he's inside oh man he has no idea okay
this is the spot for me
this is the spot because if this can be
properly hidden all right there we go
straight down all the way down to
bedrock this is the one
please don't be lava huh
i can't believe that
this better be worth it this better be
worth it okay we're at the bottom in
theory if we just head south from this
direction we should meet up with the
existing tunnel
there it is
that's a long way to transport the
zombies
that's a really long way
but nonetheless i've committed to this
now
i've risked far too much we've got we've
got the hole to the surface
and now we need to actually set this all
up we are going for it
i could be doing something productive
like getting diamond armor or getting
enchanted instead
i'm pranking scar who hasn't even
finished his big dirt house
now in order to make this work i
actually need to go in through the
bottom
and place the water in from the top so
we're gonna have to do another sneaker
but scar's pretty occupied with his
building he's probably not gonna notice
me so if i head round the outside of
this he probably won't even see me
coming
there he is
what on earth is he building
the entrance should be somewhere around
here
come on i need you i just need two
seconds of your time away from he's
focused he's focused all right we're
gonna pop that there we put the water
here and there we go okay
job done job done job done there we go
there we go there we go mission
successful
and we're safe
we got the we got the soul sand now
all we got to do is start pushing the
zombies
the next part of this mission is one of
the most dangerous parts of this mission
in order for this to work properly i
need to add kelp all the way up to the
top
so hopefully i'm not gonna drown
that would suck and also hopefully scar
doesn't see me if i make make it through
this without scar seeing me at all i
will be
a hero oh no i'm gonna die
okay okay so you need to literally get
to the top i don't know where i don't
know where scar is
and then i'm going to pop that there
i need to get enough air to make it down
to the bottom
and then i
go down dive dive dive dive dive dive
dive drive dive dive dive and the
bubbles
the bubbles
yeah okay i can't see any bubbles but
there's definitely bubbles sweet that
means that the the zombies are ready to
go right now we've got a lot of we've
got a lot of water buckets and signage
to to take care of
okay so this in theory should work now
getting making my way all the way back
is gonna be slow in fact it might be
faster just to go around again i made it
back all we got to do now is actually
set up the spawner in
in its entirety so now we got to put the
water down and get rid of the lights and
hopefully not die in the process because
dying is actually quite a nightmare it
might seem like just a clip and a cut
away for you but it's about half an
hour's worth of of grinding back stuff
for us
okay let's go and
the main thing that's annoying about
when you die
is is actually the level loss you lose a
lot of levels oh the zombies are coming
zombies are coming there shouldn't be a
too much of an issue now actually
[Music]
it's it's spawning quite a lot now
so all i gots to do is put myself in a
safe place
and they should just head on through
into there
so right i've got my camera account on
it's spawning zombies out the wazoo like
really quite a lot of zombies so now
what we do is we hide ourselves in this
little pocket here
stick a light on and let's take a look
on the camera count
here we see scar he's going ahead and
he's doing his base little does he know
that over here
there is a big tunnel
that's soon gonna be checking out
zombies absolutely everywhere let's see
how they're getting on
they are slowly making their way
yes
this is so perfect so there i am looking
i'm sorry you're so handsome so look at
this they are they're making their way
through
wow yeah they don't even stop i haven't
got any any clogs in the system any any
issues and then they get to the end and
they they just push themselves through
and then they get sent right up to the
top
and here they go
it worked oh let's see if he figures it
out
oh no scar i didn't i
didn't mean for you to die
not like this
no like this
run scar
if you're gonna die run
[Laughter]
what are you doing
oh he's gonna go look at him one more
get run away run away
he's fighting them
ah so now we gotta see how long this is
gonna take scar to fix he's just gonna
go back to building
he hasn't even figured out that this
there's something going on
[Laughter]
this is hilarious i thought he'd go oh
why there's so many zombies coming along
ah it is to be fair look it is quite
hidden you wouldn't expect it
it doesn't look suspicious at all
this was so worth it
oh my goodness
did you see that little head no you're
just like yeah what's up
[Applause]
oh he's close to figuring it out
[Music]
he must be is he not is he not slightly
curious where all these zombies are
coming from where where's the army out
there was loads of them
they're not quite making their way
they keep vanishing i think they keep
despawning on the way look oh there's a
there's a horde of them dun dun dun dun
[Music]
how many of them actually make it to the
end though
oh there goes one they are definitely
despawning while they're traveling
ah most of them aren't making it all the
way there's a there seems to be like a
gap here where they they despawn
so i think what we could do
is kind of just leave the camera count
here and just see how long it takes scar
to work it all out he's just uh he's
building away so we'll leave him to it
shall we
[Music]
go on scar
you get him
i think he's looking he's definitely he
whoa whoa whoa what
what is going on i had nothing to do
with that
scars i think scar might be looking for
what's going on but he's um he's
definitely gone the wrong direction oh
no oh no
oh he's found it he's found it
oh he's found it
oh no he's he's i've been rumbled
i think we should go up and speak to him
because i mean this was i've been
watching this for about half an hour now
35 minutes i've been watching scar
suffer
absolutely hilarious i genuinely don't
know if scar knows
if i'm his neighbor or not so
maybe we'll go and reveal ourselves to
him now no wait he saw me he saw me he
saw me uh borrowing his wheat
let's go is it i see i see what you've
going on jungle bandit
[Laughter]
why aren't they attacking is he just
immune to them now
whoa whoa
oh no
i turned it off
i turned it off scar
[Music]
hello
jungle bandit
dude you know i'm a slow typer i'm
trying to type in the zombies they're
killing me over here
i'm sorry i'm so i i've been watching
you now for about 35 minutes
and it's ju it just went from from event
to event how long did it take you to
realize that those zombies weren't
natural
well i mean once the drowns started
coming i had my suspicions suspicions
were had at the drowns
but my my ability to act on this
knowledge was like minimum i'm like well
that seems weird you know something
seems up here and finally dude i
literally saw a zombie like fly out of
that hole and i'm like
i have been working on this for a couple
of hours oh man right i have officially
turned it off it's it's done i've had my
fun um as a reward for your for your
good patience and your uh good
sportsmanship i will pick i'm i'm
no i'm not gonna make you a diamond pit
i don't have any diamonds
dude i've been i've been mining for four
hours and i found nothing but what i
will let you use is the zombie spawner
that i used to prank you just now i will
let you use it um as an xp farm i'm
gonna set one up now and then you can
use it to uh repair the tools that you
currently don't own do you do you know
where at my base is i'm i'm your
next-door neighbor i saw you come out of
the jungle and that's why you are the
jungle bandit so are you over here where
are you just around the corner from you
wait are you living in a giant meatball
no but it looks like a meatball now it's
cooked meatball now that we've done that
we actually need to make this into a
real xp farm
okay i've
now that we've done that we need to turn
this into a real xp farm so let's head
over it's this should take barely a
second
in theory this is all that we really
need
and then the zombits will come down here
and then they're ready to be harvested
for their sweet sweet rotten fl i mean
xp
in theory this is all that we basically
need they should come
up that water spout fall down take some
damage and be ready to be harvested and
i've got myself a little room in here i
mean it's not pretty but it should do so
we take away the light and away we go
right the zombies are piling
hey
[Applause]
zombie delivery system
perfect
now we just afk here for a while
and all should be good i made some
slight alterations just so that uh my uh
my diamond sword here can get just one
one shot them all
but yeah this is now done i've now got
enough xp to enchant my diamond pickaxe
so now we can go and do that
now where do i want to make it see i
actually want to create a nice front to
the house here and i think there's like
a really nice spot up here to create a
window so
i think i want my enchanting room to be
up here i think the easiest way to start
this is to actually head up to here make
the window and then make the room the
the wrong way
so start here and work my way down yeah
that looks like it's gonna be that's
gonna be big enough
perfect so
we'll quickly build this
in fact i might actually do a quick time
lapse to show the whole thing being made
super quick and then we can crack on
with putting this enchanting table down
the minimal building that i want to do
is a hobbit hole but i kind of want to
try and reinvent the hobbit hole hobby
hole is only one story tall but i
actually want to see if i can make this
entire mountain front feel like a hobbit
hole but also decorate it a bit more so
we'll see how that goes over the next
few episodes there we go starter base
front door made now i'm not exactly
finished or happy with it but i want to
transform using this
vague hobbit holy kind of design i want
to transform this whole u-shape that
i've got here i really wish i'd put that
window just two blocks to the left just
two it would have fit it's just a little
bit too close to the moment i will move
it but probably not today because i
think we're pretty much out of time for
our first episode all of this stuff
believe it or not has taken me a full
three days to get started man things are
slow right at the beginning so what we
can do while we're here is
actually get our first pick enchanted
efficiency
for oh that was it
ouch
ouch ouch ouch because i really really
need fortune
i really need fortune
let's see what we get on here silk touch
oh
silk touches efficiency and i'm breaking
three
that is pretty good now all there is to
do is well i need more xp so
down into the xp farm i go
i'm gonna get
what i need enchanted on all of this
stuff but
this is a cycle that i'm gonna have to
do several times to get exactly what i
need so i think for now
i'm gonna have to say thank you very
much for watching look i've got my
diamonds waiting as soon as i have my
fortune pickaxe i'm just gonna boop and
i'm gonna take all of these diamonds and
hopefully get more than just three i've
been saving them that are down here for
a while i can't remember where all of
them are but i've basically left most of
them exposed so that i can get
uh better enchantments but for now what
we need to do we need to get some more
zombies going some more xp some more
enchantments just to get ourselves
started so
i want to say a thank you
so much for watching i can't wait to see
what season seven is going to bring us
and i will see you
in the next episode thank you very much
for watching and good
bye